宛若明月  晚星闪耀
The moon star is shinning bright.
向之祈愿  坚信不疑
So make a wish and hold on tight.
今夜星空  魔幻弥漫
There's magic in the air tonight.
万事万物  皆有可能
And anything can happen.
就在那一刻  丑陋的小青蛙
Just in that moment, the ugly little frog
抬起那双忧郁且圆圆的眼睛恳求道
Looked up with his sad round eyes and pleaded,
求您了  亲爱的公主
"Oh please, dear Princess,
只有您的吻能够破除
Only a kiss from you can break this terrible spell
邪恶的女巫施在我身上的诅咒
that was inflicted on me by a wicked witch."
下面是我最喜欢的部分
Here comes my favourite part.
美丽的公主被他悲惨的遭遇打动了
And the beautiful princess was so moved
她俯下身
by him desperately that she stooped down,
捡起这个滑溜溜的生物  身子前倾
picked up the slippery creature, leaned forward,
把小青蛙捧到她的唇边并吻了他
raised him to her lips and kissed that little frog.
之后  青蛙变成了英俊的王子
Then, the frog was transformed into a handsome prince.
他们结了婚  从此幸福的生活在了一起
They were married and lived happy ever after.
结束
The end.
再读一遍  再读一遍
Read it again, read it again.
抱歉  夏洛特  斯坦福快到家了
Sorry Charlotte. Stanford would be at home.
该说晚安了  蒂亚纳
Say good night. Tiana.
我绝对不会
There is no way in this whole wide world,
永远不会  亲一只青蛙
I would ever ever ever, I mean never, kiss a frog.
太恶心了
Yuck!
真的吗
Is that so?
这就是你的白马王子  蒂亚纳
Well, here's your Prince Charming, Tiana.
来  亲他
Come on, kiss him!
不
No.
亲他
Kiss him!
住手
Stop it!
亲他  亲他  亲他
Kiss kiss kiss it!
我不要  我不要  我不要
I won't! I won't! I won't!
我会
I will do it.
我愿意亲一只青蛙
I will kiss a frog.
如果可以遇见王子  成为公主
I would kiss a hundred frogs so far
我愿意亲一百只青蛙
to meet a prince and to be a princess.
女孩们  别再折磨这只可怜的小猫了
You girls, stop tormenting that poor little kitty.
可怜的小家伙
Poor thing.
晚上好  优朵拉
Evening, Eudora.
爸爸  爸爸  看我的新裙子
Daddy! Daddy! Look at my new dress.
漂亮吧
Isn't it pretty?
瞧你
Haha. Look at you!
新奥尔良最好的裁缝
Well, I expect nothing less from
真是不负厚望啊
the finest suit cuisine of New Orleans.
我想要那条裙子
Oh, I want that dress.
现在不行  甜心
Not now, sugar palm.
我想要  求你了  求你了  求你了
I want that one, please, please, please, please...
优朵拉  你能做件类似的吗
Eudora, you suppose you can web something up like that?
绝对没问题
Anything for my best customer.
走吧  蒂亚纳
Come along, Tiana.
你爸爸下班现在该到家了
Your dad should be home from work by now.
好了  公主
Okay, right now, princess.
你虽然会得到那条裙子  但不许再要了
You're getting that dress but that's it!
不准欺人太甚
No Bouff has to pushover.
有人想要小狗吗
Now who wants the puppy?
小狗  我要  我要
Puppy...I do. I do.
小狗太可爱了
Puppy is so cute!
秋葵汤闻起来不错  蒂亚纳
Gumbos smell good, Tiana.
应该可以喝了  爸爸
I think it's done, daddy.
是吗  你确定吗
Yeah, you sure?
真的肯定吗
Absolutely positive?
是的
Yes.
我要把这一勺汤放进我的
Okay, I'm about to put this spoon in my...
等等
Wait!
好了
Done.
怎样
What?
甜心
Well, sweetheart.
这是我喝过的最美味的秋葵汤
This is the best gumbo I've ever tasted.
过来
Come here.
优朵拉  这孩子真有天赋
Eudora, our girl got a gift.
我告诉过你的
I thought I told you that.
这个天赋应该和大家一起分享
A gift that's best just gotta be shared.
大家伙  我做了秋葵汤
Hey, everybody. I made gumbo.
闻起来不错
Oh, that smells good.
我家还有几只小狗  蒂亚纳
I've got some house puppies, Tiana.
美食的好处就是可以
You know the thing about good food...
让各行各业的朋友聚到一起
it brings folks together from all walks of life.
同时温暖他们的内心
It warms them right up
让他们的脸上浮现出笑容
and it puts a smile on their faces.
等我开一家自己的餐馆之后
And, and when I open my own restaurant,
肯定会有人排队等候
I take a bid people gonna line up,
队伍有几英里长  只为常一常我的美食
for miles around just to get a taste of my food.
我们的美食
Our food.
说得对  宝贝
That's right, baby.
我们的美食
Our food.
蒂亚纳餐厅
爸爸  看啊
Daddy, look.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
夏洛特的童话书上说过
Charlotte's fairytale book said,
如果对着晚星许愿
If you make a wish on the evening star,
愿望就会实现
it sure would come true.
那你就对着那颗星许愿吧  宝贝
Well, you wish on that star, sweetheart.
许愿后  你的小小心灵会追寻梦想
Yes, you wish and you dream with all your little heart.
但是记住  蒂亚纳  那颗
But you remember, Tiana, that...
那颗奇特的星星只会让你离梦想更远
that odd star can only take you part away.
你必须自己克服困难
You gotta help along with some hard work of your own.
之后才能做你决心要做的事
And then, yeah, you can do anything you set your mind to.
答应爸爸一件事
Just promise your daddy one thing.
永远不要忽视真正重要的事
That you'll never ever lose sight of what's really important,
好吗
okay?
明早见  宝贝  亲亲
See you in the morning, baby. Kiss.
睡吧
Get some sleep.
求你了  求你了  求你了
Please. Please. Please.
蒂亚纳小姐  昨晚小费虽少
Well, Miss Tiana. Rough night for tips
但积少成多
but every little penny counts.
别担心  爸爸
Don't you worry, daddy.
很快就能实现了
We'll be there soon.
晚安  奶牛
Good night, cows.
早安  伯爵
Good morning, dukes.
南方大地  有城一座
In the South Land, there's a city.
公主与青蛙
矗立河边
Way down on the river.
烹饪杂志
窈窕淑女  君子好逑
Where the women are very pretty and all the men deliver.
音乐悠扬
They got music.
此起彼伏
It's always playing.
从早到晚  整夜欢歌
Start in the day time, go all through the night.
若闻乐声
When you hear that music playing,
如闻我言  请君自便
Hear what I'm saying and make it feel alright.
伯爵咖啡
邀友同行  并肩前往
Grab somebody, come on down.
手握画笔  美化城邦
Bring your paintbrush, we're painting the town.
香飘四溢
Oh, there's some sweetness going around.
一切尽在  新奥尔良
Catch it down in New Orleans.
巫术  魔法  预知你的未来
精彩迷幻  魔力无边
We got magic, good and maze.
如愿以偿  梦想成真
Make it happen, make it real, say.
有得必有失
If everything you want is lose what you have.
这就是新奥尔良
Down here in New Orleans.
伙伴你好  切勿羞涩
Hey partner, don't be shy.
敬请光临  一览何妨
Come on down here and give us a try.
若要享受人生
You wanna do some living before you die.
就要来新奥尔良
Do it down in New Orleans.
王子今日驾到
古老质朴  庄园宅邸
Stale homes and mansions
制糖作坊  棉花糖香
Of the sugar darns and cotton candies.
无论贫富  皆有梦想
Rich people, poor people all got dreams.
梦想可成真  就在新奥尔良
Dreams do come true in New Orleans.
上菜
Order up!
再来一杯咖啡  服务员
Another coffee here, chief.
马上就来
Coming right up for you.
早上好  蒂亚纳
Hey, Tiana.
早上好  乔治娅
Morning, Georgia.
最近好吗  蒂亚纳
Hey, how are you doing, Tiana?
你好
Hey, yo.
我们今晚要去舞会
We are going out dancing tonight.
你也来吧
You can join us?
来吧  蒂亚纳
Come on, Tiana.
你可以做我的舞伴
You can dance with me.
你们都知道我不懂跳舞的
You know I've got two left feet.
还有  我  给你餐巾  宝贝
Besides, I... you need napkins, sweetheart.
我还得加班
I'm gonna work for a double shift to...
您的蛋糕
Here, your hot cakes.
所以我
You know, so I...
你就能存钱开餐馆了
So you can save for your restaurant.
我明白  我理解
I know, I know.
姑娘  你就知道工作
Girl, all you ever do is work.
上菜
Order up!
或许下次吧
Maybe next time.
我说过她不会去的
I told you, she wouldn't come.
你们又在谈论那该死的餐馆吗
Are you talking about the damn restaurant again?
比福德  你的鸡蛋要糊了
Buford, your eggs are burning.
你攒多少钱都付不起那些租金的
You ain't never get enough for that damned payment.
已经差不多了
I'm getting close.
那还差多少
Yeah, how close?
我的煎饼呢
Where's my Flapjacks?
忘掉开饭馆吧
You gotta forget about the motive of
如果你真能开饭馆
getting that restaurant,
那我就能中彩票了
as I do in winning The Kentucky Derby.
为我工作吧
Settle me up, yo.
早上好  拉布福先生
Morning Mr. La Bouff.
早上好  蒂亚纳
Good morning, Tiana.
祝贺您被选为
Congratulations on you,
嘉年华仪式的国王
being voted to be King of Mardi Gras.
太出乎我意料了
It caught me completely by surprise
连续5年当选
for the fifth year in a row.
我要庆祝一下  来点
Now, how about I celebrate with...
您的鸡蛋豆饼
Your eggs.
这是第一炉  就等您来呢
I got the first batch, just waiting for you.
在我走之前再来几盘
Well, keep them coming till I pass out.
蒂亚纳  蒂亚纳  蒂亚纳
Tiana  Tiana  Tiana
你看新闻了吗
Did you hear the news?
告诉她  告诉她  老爸
Tell her. Oh, tell her, Big Daddy.
是的  纳温王子
Oh yeah, Prince Naveen...
马耳其顿的纳温王子要来新奥尔良
Prince Naveen of Maldonia is coming to New Orleans.
我们要见面啦
Oh, he even meets me.
告诉她你都做了什么  老爸
Oh, tell her what you did, Big Daddy.
告诉她
Tell her!
我邀请了
Well, I invited...
老爸邀请王子参加
Big Daddy invited the Prince Charming
今晚的化妆舞会
to a masquerade ball tonight.
告诉她你还做了什么  老爸
Oh, tell her what else you did, Big Daddy.
继续
Go on.
他住在
And he stays in...
And he stays, oh...
他将作为私人贵宾住在我们家
And he stays in our house as my personal guest.
洛特  太好了
Oh, Lotte. That's swell.
另外一点建议
Other word for advice.
我妈妈说过
My mama always said that
要抓住男人心的
the quickest way to a man's heart,
必须先抓住他的胃
is through his stomach.
说的没错
That's it.
发生了什么
What just happened?
蒂亚纳  你真是个绝顶天才
Oh, Tiana. You're a born out genius.
今晚我的舞会要预定500个
I would need about 500
另男人神魂颠倒的鸡蛋豆饼
of your men catching Binayas for my ball tonight.
抱歉  爸爸
Excuse me, daddy.
这是我的订金
This is my coverage.
这些足够了  洛特
Well, this coverage's just fine, Lotte.
这就是我要的
This is it.
我要有自己的餐馆了
I'm getting my restaurant.
今晚我的王子终于还要降临了
Tonight my prince's finally coming.
我发誓不会让他跑掉的
And I swear I won't let him go.
芬内兄弟地产
房子看来很干净  芬内先生
Everything looks pretty clean, Mr. Fenner.
芬内先生
And Mr. Fenner...
明早太阳一升起
We'll have all the paperwork ready to sign.
我们就签约
First thing after the morning glow.
我有个更好的提议
I'll do you one better.
今晚在拉布福的大型舞会上碰面
Why don't I sign them tonight
然后签约怎么样
when I see you all at the La Bouff's great ball?
你真心急啊  蒂亚纳
You drive a hot pot, Tiana.
一个人  谢谢
Table for one, please.
妈妈
Oh, mama.
送你一点东西帮你开张
Here's a little something to help you get started.
爸爸的秋葵汤锅
Oh, daddy's gumbo pot.
我明白
I know.
我也很想他
I missed him too.
好了  快点  开门吧
Well now, hurry up and open the door.
快来瞧  妈妈
Look at it, mama.
有没有种想哭的感觉
Doesn't it just make you wanna cry?
是啊
Yes.
你站的地方的右边会有个收银台
We'll make the deals on right at where you're standing.
那边会有个厨房
Oh, and over here, a gourmet kitchen.
还有  天花板上
And, and here from the ceiling,
会有一盏大大的水晶吊灯
a big all crystal chandelier here.
真不愧是你爸爸的女儿
You're your daddy's daughter, alright.
他以前也总是不停地唠叨这些
Used to go on and on about this old sugar mill too.
亲爱的
Petite cakes.
我相信这地方会焕然一新的
I'm sure this place is gonna be just wonderful.
但糟糕的是你会很辛苦
But it's a shame you're working so hard.
但我怎能在马上成功时半途而废呢
But how can I let up now when I am so close.
我得确保爸爸的艰辛
I've gotta make sure all daddy's
得到应有的回报
hard work means something.
蒂亚纳  或许你爸爸没能得到
Tiana, your daddy may not have gotten the place
你梦想中的房子  但他拥有比这更好的
you always wanted but he had something better.
他拥有爱
He had love.
这也是我唯一希望你能得到的  宝贝
That's all I want for you, sweetheart.
遇见你的白马王子
To meet your Prince Charming
从此之后与他快乐的共舞
and dance off into your happily ever after.
妈妈  我没有时间跳舞
Mama, I don't have time for dances.
这件事只能先等等
That's just gonna have to wait a while.
到底要等多久
How long are we talking about here?
光阴似水  弥足珍贵
Ain't got time for messing around.
虚度光阴  非我本性
And it's not my style.
我要抱外孙
I want some grandkids.
慵懒之城  催人倦怠
This whole town can slow you down.
驱使众人  择易而行
People taking the easy way.
我心所欲  了然于心
But I know exactly where I'm going to get.
日有所新  日渐接近
And getting closer, closer, everyday.
成功之日  已不远矣
And I'm almost there, I'm almost there.
众人笑我疯狂  但是我心依旧
People down here think I'm crazy but I don't care.
陷阱磨难  我皆不惧
Traps and tribulations have had my share.
如今势不可挡
There ain't nothing gonna stop me now
而我势在必得
cause I'm almost there.
爸爸曾说  童话亦可成真
I remember Daddy told me: "Fairytales can come true."
实现与否  全权在你
You gotta make 'em happen, it all depends on you."
谨遵此言  勤奋不懈
So I work real hard each and every day.
果不其然  事随我愿
Now, things, for sure are going my way.
如愿以偿
Just doing what I do.
瞧瞧吧  伙计们  成功之日  已不远矣
Look out boys, I'm coming through.
成功之日  已不远矣
And I'm almost there.
I'm almost there.
八方宾客  汇聚一堂
People gonna come here from everywhere.
成功之日  已不远矣
And I'm almost there.
I'm almost there.
陷阱磨难
There has been traps and tribulations.
我皆不惧
You know I have had my share.
爬过高山
But I've climbed the mountain.
趟过河流
I've crossed the river.
成功之日  已不远矣
And I'm almost there.
I'm almost there.
成功之日  已不远矣
I'm almost there!
借过
Excuse me.
需要帮忙吗  老兄
You need a hand there, buddy?
好样的
Oh... yes!
他在跳舞
Well, he's dancing.
少爷  我在到处找你
Sir, I've been looking for you everywhere.
真巧  劳伦斯
Oh, what a coincidence, Lawrence.
我在到处躲你
I've been avoiding you everywhere.
化装舞会要迟到了
We're going to be late for the masquerade.
听着  劳伦斯  听着
Listen, Lawrence. Listen.
太棒了  爵士乐
Oh... yes. Jazz music.
原本这里很无聊
It was boring here.
但你们的出现增添了美感
It's beautiful, you know.
不行
No hope.
和我跳舞吧  胖墩先生
Oh, dance with me, fat man.
放松点  老兄
Stay loose, bro.
你现在该在舞会上
You should be in the ball right now.
是的  是的  是的
Yes. Yes. Yes.
但首先  我想请这里所有人喝一杯
But first, I'll buy everyone here a drink.
拿什么请
With what?
说到这  你有两个选择
At this point, you have two choices.
娶一个富婆或是
You would marry a rich lady or...
找份工作
get a job!
好吧
Alright.
Fine.
但首先  我们要跳舞
But first, we dance!
因为有人看不到自己的双脚
For someone who cannot see his feet.
得了吧  骗人的
Come on, you lie on this.
太完美了
This is perfect.
你终于融入音乐了
You've finally got into the music.
你听懂我的笑话了吗
Do you get my joke?
因为你的头  被大号罩住了
Because your head is... it's in a tuba.
帮我拿下来
Get me out!
好吧
Alright then.
抓紧
Hold on.
你还笑
You're grinning?
从来没人这样对待过我
I've never been something agitated.
你们好
Hello?
先生们  很高兴见到你们
Gentlemen, enchanté.
法兹利尔博士向你们问好
A tip of the hat from Dr. Facilier.
你好吗
How are you doing?
塔罗牌占卜师
Tarot readings.
护身符  魔药  帮你梦想成真
Charms, potions, dreams made real.
这都是骗人的
[speaks Maldonian]
什么 我像个赌徒吗
What? Were I a betting man?
当然不像  我不喜欢碰运气
And I'm not, I stay away from games of chance.
少爷
Sire!
我感到我正和来访的王室成员同行
Ah, I'd wager I'm in the company of visiting royalty.
劳伦斯  劳伦斯
Lawrence  Lawrence
这位大师刚刚看了我的手相
This remarkable gentleman has just read my palm.
或者他是看了今早的报纸
Or this morning's newspaper.
少爷  这家伙明显不是好人
Sire, this cat is obviously a Satan.
我建议我们去个
And I suggest we move on to a less...
你竟敢对我不敬  小矮子
Don't you disrespect me, little man!
竟敢诽谤和嘲笑我
Don't you derogate or deride.
你们在我的地盘上  不是你们的地盘
You're in my world now, not your world.
法兹利尔巫师  巫术商店
另一边有我的同党
And I got friends on the other side.
另一边有他的同党
He's got friends on the other side...
那是回声  先生们
That's an echo, gentlemen.
只是路易斯安那的一点风物
Just a little something we have here in Louisiana.
接待来宾的小把戏  别担心
A little parlour trick. Don't worry.
坐到我的桌边
Sit down at my table.
放松心情
Put your minds at ease.
你们若能放松  我就能随心所欲
If you relax it will enable me to do anything I please.
我能预见你们的未来
I can read your future.
亦能改变些许未来
I can change it around some, too.
我会审视你们的内心和灵魂
I'll look deep into your heart and soul.
你有灵魂吧  有吗  劳伦斯
You do have a soul, don't you, Lawrence?
实现你们最迫切的梦想
Make your wildest dreams come true.
我会巫术
I got Voodoo.
我会魔法
I got hoodoo.
我还有未曾尝试过的宝物
I got thing I hadn't even tried!
另一边还有我的同党
And I got friends on the other side.
另一边有他的同党
He's got friends on the other side...
牌  牌  牌能预言
The cards, the cards, the cards will tell.
过去  现在  还有未来
The past, the present and the future as well.
牌  牌  抽三张
The cards, the cards, just take three.
和我一同看看你的未来
Take a little trip into your future with me.
你  年轻人  来自大洋彼岸
Now you, young man are from across the sea.
你的父母都是王室成员
You come from two long lines of royalty.
我的母亲也曾是王室成员
I'm a royal myself on my mother's side.
你们的生活方式虽高调  资金却短缺
Your lifestyle's high but your funds are low.
你得娶个有钱人家的千金
You need to marry a little honey whose daddy got dough.
爸妈不给你零用钱了吧  花花公子
Mommy and daddy cut you off, huh, playboy?
没错
Eh, that's the truth.
你现在得找人结婚
Now you all gotta get hitched,
但婚姻将束缚你
But hitching ties you down.
你只想要自由
You just wanna be free.
穿梭于世界各地
Hop from place to place.
自由需要绿色的牌
But freedom takes green!
绿色的牌
It's the green.
你需要绿色的牌
It's the green you need.
当我窥探你未来的时候
And when I looked into your future,
我看到了绿色
It's the green that I see.
而你  小矮子  我不想在你身上浪费时间
On you little man, I don't want to waste much time.
你一生都在被人摆布
You've been pushed around all your life.
被你妈妈摆布
You've been pushed around by your mother
被你的兄弟姐妹摆布
And your sister and your brother.
如果你结了婚
And if you was married,
还会被你老婆摆布
You'd be pushed around by your wife.
但在未来  我所看到你
But in your future, the you I see,
会成为你向往已久的那个人
Is exactly the man you always wanted to be.
和我握手吧
Shake my hand.
快  伙计们
Come on, boys.
难道不敢和可怜的恶棍握手吗
Won't you shake the poor sinner's hand?
很好
Yes.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
变身中心
Transformation central.
改造中心
Reformation central.
变形中心
Transmogrification central.
感觉到了吗
Can you feel it?
你在变化  你在变化
You're changing, you're changing,
你在变化  好了
You're changing, alright.
愿你满意
I hope you're satisfied.
若不满意  不要怪我
But if you ain't, don't blame me.
要怪就怪我那边的同党
You can blame my friends on the other side.
有失必有得
You got what you wanted, but you lost what you had.
约翰逊议员
Ah, Senator Johnson.
你好  妖怪
Hey, Genie.
希望您能为您的选民
I hope you'll leave some of your bean eggs
留点鸡蛋豆饼
For your constituents.
给  滚烫的
Here you go. Piping hot.
斯特拉  抱歉
S...Stella. Excuse us.
斯特拉  不行  不行
Stella, no. No.
好吧  但只有一个
Okay, but just one.
夏洛特小姐  您两小时前就让我等
But Miss Charlotte, you said "later" two hours ago.
崔维斯  当女士让你等的时候
Travis, when a woman  says "later",
她真正的意思是"不行"
She really means "not ever".
好了  闪一边去
Now run along.
这有数不清的年轻美女
There are plenty of young belles done for you
你很容易就能钓到她们
to walk them into a stooper.
给我餐巾  快
Give me those napkins quick.
干什么用
What do you use that for?
我像在教堂赎罪的人一样紧张
I sweat, I'm sweating like a sinner in church.
天啊  来得也太迟了
Oh dear, it's getting a bit so late.
这有那么多骑士
There are still a few chevaliers.
这不公平
This is not fair.
我的王子永远不会来了
My prince is never coming.
不会的  洛特
No, Lotte
我永远都得不到我想要的
I'll never get what I wish for.
洛特  等等
Lotte, wait!
冷静下来
Just calm down.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
或许我该更虔诚的祈祷
Maybe I've just gotta wish harder.
求你了  求你了  求你了  求你了
Please, please, please, please...
洛特  你不能只对着星星许愿  除非
Lotte, you can't just wish on the star, expect things...
女士们先生们  纳温王子殿下驾到
Ladies and gentlemen, the Royal Highness, Prince Naveen.
蒂亚纳  晚上好
Evening, Tiana.
多美妙的聚会啊
Marvellous party.
晚上好  芬内先生
Evening, Mr. Fenner.
芬内先生
And Mr. Fenner...
我闻到了鸡蛋豆饼的味道
I smell of bean eggs.
等我们签好合同
Gotta be the house specialty
这会是餐厅的特色菜
once I sign those papers you all brought.
关于那件事
Yes. About that, erm...
我们不能卖给你了
You won't be in.
什么
What?
有人以现金支付了全部房款
A fellow came in and offered the whole amount in cash.
除非你在周三前给出更高的价钱
Unless you could top his offer about on Wednesday.
不然就只能和那里说拜拜了
You can kiss that place goodbye.
你们  你们知道我为了攒钱有多不容易吗
You, you know how long it took me to save that money?
完全理解
Exactly.
所以  像你这种身份的女人
Which is why a little woman of your background,
是无法游刃有余地管理
wouldn't have the hands full,
那么大的生意的
trying out a big business like that.
你还是放弃吧
Now, you better off, will you?
不  等等
No, wait a minute...
虽然没有鸡蛋豆饼了  还是算了吧
No, no bean eggs though.
站住
Now, now hold on there.
你们回来
You guys come back here...
蒂亚纳  是用美食
Tiana, time to hit Prince Charming
征服白马王子的时候了
with those men kitchen bean you've...
怎么回事
What happened?
我  我只是
I...I... I just...
亲爱的  真可怜
Oh, you poor dear.
纳温王子
Oh, Prince Naveen.
我很快就回来  甜心
I'll be right back, sugar.
我有件非常适合你的衣服
I've got just the dress for you.
小蒂  亲爱的  你看到他和我跳舞了吗
Oh, Tia, honey. Did you see the way he danced with me?
他很快就会向我求婚的
A marriage proposal can't be far behind.
谢谢你  晚星
Thank you, Evening Star!
大人们总是说
You know, I was taught to think
只有小孩和疯子才会对星星许愿
that wishing on a star was just for babies and crazy people.
天哪  看看你自己
Look at you!
你就像五月的木兰花一样美丽
Oh, aren't you just as pretty as a Magnolia on May?
我们小时候许下梦幻般的愿望
Seems like only yesterday we were both little girls
就像昨天的事一样
dreaming our fairytale dreams.
而今天  这些愿望终于实现了
And tonight they're finally coming true.
好了  继续努力吧
Well, back into the fray.
祝我好运吧  纳温王子
Wish me luck. Oh Prince Naveen!
只差一点
Almost...
只差一点就成功
Almost there.
人们从四面八方而来
People would have come from everywhere.
差一点就成功了
I was almost there...
真不敢相信我也会这样做
I cannot believe I'm doing this.
求你了  求你了  求你了
Please, please, please.
真搞笑
Oh, very funny.
怎么样
So, what now?
我猜你想要一个吻吗
I reckon you want a kiss?
一个吻听起来不错  来吧
Kissing would be nice, yes?
抱歉  抱歉  抱歉
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我  我不想吓你的
I didn't... I didn't mean to scare you.
我  别  别  别
I... No, no, no, no...
等等  住手
Wait. Hold on.
公主  你的双臂很有力嘛
You have a very strong arm, princess.
好啦  请住手
Okay, please.
把玩具猴放下
Put the monkey down.
退后  不然我就  我就
Stay back or I'll... I'll...
等等  等等
Please, please, please, please...
请允许我介绍一下自己
Well, allow me to introduce myself.
我是纳温王子
I am Prince Naveen...
从马耳其顿来
... of Maldonia.
王子
Prince?
但我并没许愿要
But I didn't wish for any...
等等  如果  如果你是王子
Hold on, if... if... if you're the prince,
那  和洛特跳舞的
then... then who was that waltzing with Lotte
又是谁
on the dance floor?
我只知道  前一分钟我还是个
All I know is one minute I am a prince,
英俊迷人  万众瞩目的王子
charming and handsome,cutting-a-rug.
等我醒来我就变成了这个样子
And the next thing I know, I'm tripping over these.
等等  等等
Wait... wait... wait...
等一下  我知道这个故事
Wait, I know this story.
青蛙王子
The Froggie Printo!
-你是说青蛙王子吗  -是的
- The Frog Prince?  - Yes.
以前我妈妈每晚
Yes, my mother had the servants
都让仆人念给我听
read this to me every night.
对了  对了
Yes, yes, yes!
这就是破解之法
This is exactly the answer.
你必须要吻我
You must kiss me.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我保证  你会享受这感觉的
You will enjoy it, I guarantee.
所有女人都会沉醉在纳温王子的香吻中
All women enjoy the kiss of Prince Naveen.
来吧  撅起嘴
Come, we pucker.
我还没适应
That's new.
我很抱歉
Look. I'm sorry.
我很想帮你
I'd really like to help you.
但我不会亲吻一只青蛙的
But I just do not kiss frogs!
但刚才在阳台上  是你问的我
But on the balcony, you asked me.
我没想到你会回答
I didn't expect you to answer!
但你必须吻我
Oh, but you must kiss me.
我不止英俊非凡
Look, besides being unbelievable handsome,
我的家庭也非常富有
I also happen to come from a fabulously wealthy family.
自然  我能给你某种报酬
Surely I can offer you some type of reward
或是满足你一个愿望
or a wish I could grant, perhaps?
可以吗
Yes?
只需要一个吻吗
Just one kiss?
只一个吻
Just one.
除非你想吻久一点
Unless you beg for more.
好了  蒂亚纳 你能做到的
Okay, Tiana. You can do this.
你能做到的
You can do this.
集中精神  看着嘴  好的
Look. Just look here. Okay.
我的天啊
[speaks Maldonian]
你没什么变化嘛
Well, you don't look that much different.
但你怎么跑到上面去了
But how did you get way up there?
我又怎么跑到下面来了  在这堆
And how did I get way down here, in all these...
别紧张  公主
Easy, Princess.
公主  别慌张
Princess, do not panic!
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me?
我变绿了  还  满身黏液
I'm green and... and I'm... I'm slimy!
不  不是黏液
No... That's not slime.
-什么  -是保护黏胶
- What?  - You're security mucus.
斯特拉
Hey Stella!
抓住那青蛙
Get that frog!
快跑
Run!
我跑不了
I can't run.
我是只青蛙
I'm a frog!
那就跳
Then hop!
跳
Hop?
快跑
Run boy!
跑啊
Run!
恶狗
Monster dog!
我来
I got this!
-小心 -小心
- Look out!  - Look out!
别挡道
Out of the way!
我们这是去哪儿
Where are we going?
借光
Excuse me.
我什么都看不到
I can't see a thing.
我也是
Neither can I...
站住  斯特拉
Wait, Stella.
要飞了
Going up.
斯特拉  别追
Stella, wait!
是我啊  蒂亚纳
It's me, Tiana.
蒂亚纳
Tiana?
斯特拉和我说话了
Stella was talking to me.
那只狗
The dog.
他刚才和我说话了
He just talked to me.
如果你一直
You know, if you're going to
被小事困扰的话
let every little thing bother you,
那今晚对你来说会相当漫长
it's going to be a very long night!
天啊
Oh dear.
你走路真轻
Oh... you're so quiet.
你把他放走了
You let him go?
瓶子太恶心了
The bottle was so disgusting.
所以我没把盖拧紧
So I've loosened the lid.
所以
And this is like... ouch!
我怎么会和巫术
How did I ever get tangled up in
扯上关系
all these voodoo madness?
我不干了
I can't get through with this.
你去带着这恶心的东西吧
You wear this, this disgusting thing!
你小心点!
Careful with that!
要是这个摔坏了  我就
Anything happens to this, I'm gonna be...
拉瑞  巫术的真谛在于
The funny fact about voodoo, Larry.
你不能控制自己的罪孽
Can't control a sin for myself.
况且  你我都知道
Besides, you and I both know
掌控天下靠的不是魔力
the real power in this world ain't magic.
而是金钱
It's money.
放手一搏吧
Buck yourself in.
那倒是
That's true.
你难道不厌倦卑微的生活吗
Aren't you tired of living on the margins?
那些富人坐在奢华的车里
While all those fat cats in their fancy cars
根本不用正眼瞧你
don't give you so much on the sideways glance.
是的  我厌倦了
Yes, I am.
你要做的就是把富老爹的小公主娶到手
All you gotta do is marry Big Daddy's little princess.
你将会得到他的
He will be splitting that juicy La Bouff fortune
一半财产
right down the middle.
说好的  六四分成
60, 40, like I said.
好啊
Yeah.
那纳温王子呢
But, what about Naveen?
那小东西很可能被轧死在路边
Your little slip-up would be a minor bumping the road.
只要保管好王子的血就行了
So long we've got the prince's blood in this.
好的
Yes.
巫术
Voodoo?
你是说这里所发生的一切
You mean to tell me these all happened
是因为你惹了一个影子巫师吗
cause you were messing with the Shadow Man?
他非常有说服力
He was very charismatic.
向星星许愿比这个好多了
It serves me right for wishing on stars.
实现愿望的唯一途径
The only way to get what you want in this world
就是努力工作
is through hard work.
努力工作
Hard work?
为什么  公主为什么要努力工作
Why... why would a princess need to work hard?
什么  我不是公主
Huh? Oh. I'm not a princess.
我是服务生
I'm a waitress.
服务生
A waitress?
难怪那个吻不起作用
Well, no wonder the kiss didn't work.
你对我撒谎
You lied to me.
我没有  我从没说过自己是公主
No, I... I never said I was a princess.
你也没说过自己是个服务生
You never said that you were a waitress!
你  你戴着皇冠
You, you... you were wearing a crown!
这是化装舞会  你这个被宠坏的富少爷
It was a costume party, you spoiled little rich boy!
好吧 你真是个蠢蛋
Oh, oh yes. Well, the egg is on your face, alright.
我才不是什么富少爷
Because I do not have any riches!
-什么 -我其实是个穷光蛋
- What?  - I am completely broke.
可你之前说你非常富有
You said you were fabulously wealthy!
不  是我的父母非常富有
No. My parents are fabulously wealthy.
但他们不给我钱  因为我是个
But they cut me off for being a...
水蛭  是水蛭
Leech! Leech!
你是个穷光蛋
You're broke?
那你还好意思说我是骗子
And you have the gall to call me a liar?
我没说谎
It was not a lie.
我正准备
I fully inte...
我正准备变得有钱
I fully intent to be rich again.
一旦我娶了夏洛特・拉布福小姐
Once I marry Miss Charlotte La Bouff
她会帮我的
and she will help me.
你是个王子吗
You're a prince?
当然是
Obviously.
她会帮你的
She'll help you!
好吧  你们两个结婚后
Alright then, when you two are married,
你要信守诺言
you are gonna keep your promise
帮我开餐馆  对吗
and get me my restaurant, right?
别心急
Not so fast.
我是对美丽的公主作出承诺
I make that promise to a beautiful princess,
可不是对你这个疯女人
not a cranky woman.
那些浮木为什么会动
Why are those logs moving?
那些不是浮木
Those aren't logs.
大木头上有牙齿哦
I've got bits on the big wood.
等等  他们要去哪儿
Wait... where, where did they go?
过来
Come here!
我咬到他们了
One taste of the muscle.
啊  那是我的尾巴
Ouch! That's my tail!
他们会找到这里吗
Know where they'll find?
你自求多福吧
Find you own dream
他在哪儿
There he is.
就是他  就是他
That's him! That's him!
帮我度过这关
Help me out of this one,
我和夏洛特结婚后就给你买餐馆
once I marry Charlotte, I should get your restaurant.
你一定很美味  比苍蝇好吃
You gonna taste so good. Tasted better than fly.
快点  快拉我一把
Quick, quick. Pull me up!
你虽然能跳  但你躲不了
You can hop, but you can't hide.
我们有一整晚的时间
We've got all night.
好了  服务员
Alright, waitress.
看来我们要在这里待一阵子了
Looks like we are going to be here for a while.
所以我们或许应该销魂一下
So we may as well get comfortable.
你这浑身黏液的东西  离我远点
Get your slimy self away from me.
我说过  这不是黏液
I told you, it is not slime!
是保护黏胶
It is mucus!
太阳晒屁股了  睡美人
Rise and shine, sleeping beauty.
鳄鱼都走了
Gators are gone.
我们要回到新奥尔良
We gotta get back to New Orleans
把你惹的这些麻烦都解决掉
and undo this mess you've got us into.
我只是一个爱胡说八道的
That was just the one parading around
花花公子而已
with the fully baloney, Tiana.
划船回家的音乐
Music to paddle back.
你还是来帮帮忙吧
I could use a little help.
帮忙
Help?
那我弹大点声吧
I will play a little louder.
如果你不要弹琴然后来
How about a little less picking and...
我知道这曲子
I know that tune!
点燃我的布鲁斯
"Jipper my blues"
继续  老兄
Play it, brother.
太棒了
Oh yeah!
我终于等到知音了
I've waited you for all my life.
你从哪里学会演奏这个的
How did you learn to play like that?
在长沼
Well, in the Bayou,
那里是世上最好的爵士乐学校
it's the best jazz school in the world.
所有伟大的音乐家都在船上演奏
All the greats play the river boats.
若能和那些人同台演出
Oh, Louis will give anything
让路易斯干什么都行
to be up there jamming with the big boys.
那你为什么不去呢
So, why don't you?
我去过一次
Oh, I tried once.
结果不太理想
It didn't end well.
见到你真的非常高兴
It has been a real pleasure meeting you.
路易斯  谢谢你没吃了我们
Louis, and thank your kindness for not eating us.
但我们最好还是上路吧
But we'd best to be on our way.
你们要去哪里
Where... where are you going?
找人解除魔咒
To find somebody to break this spell.
什么魔咒
What spell?
听好  我的朋友
Brace yourself, my scaly friend.
我们不是青蛙
We are not frogs.
我们是人类
We are humans.
你没开玩笑吗
You are serious?
我是马耳其顿的纳温王子
I am Naveen, Prince of Maldonia.
她是服务生蒂亚纳
And she is Tiana, the waitress.
别亲她
Do not kiss her.
让我来说吧
Now, just a second.
这个年轻人被巫术
This groom here got himself turned
变成了青蛙
into a frog by a voodoo man.
-如今 -巫术
- And now... - Voodoo?
就是欧迪婆婆用的法术吗
Like the kind Mama Odie do?
欧迪婆婆
Mama Odie?
欧迪婆婆   她是长沼的巫术女王
Mama Odie. She's the voodoo queen of the bayou.
她会魔法  咒语以及各种巫术
She got magic and spells, all kind of voodoo.
你能带我们去找她吗
Could you take us to her?
到长沼深处的黑暗森林中去吗
To the deepest, darkest part of the bayou?
被飞刀利器追杀
Facing razors, sharp backup machines
或被猎枪杀死吗
that trap us and hunt us with guns?!
不可能
No.
学着点
Watch and learn.
路易斯
Louis.
我们不能帮你实现愿望真是太遗憾了
It's too bad we cannot help you with your dream.
如果你个头小一点  牙再少一点
If only you were smaller, less toothy.
给观众演奏时就
You could play jazz to the darling crowds
不会吓到他们了
without scaring them.
无所谓了  享受孤独吧  朋友
Anyway, enjoy your loneliness, my friend.
祝你幸福
Apprécier
不错
Cute.
但是不会
But it's not gonna...
各位  我有个疯狂的主意
Hey guys, I... I just have a crazy idea.
让欧迪婆婆把我变成人类怎么样
What if I asked Mama Odie to turn me human?
路易斯  你是个天才
Louis, you are a genius.
哈利路亚
Halleluiah!
如果变成人类  我就直奔新奥尔良
If I were human being, I'd head straight for New Orleans.
用心吹响这只小号
And I'd blow this horn, so hot and strong.
没人像我一样卖力
Like no one they'd ever seen.
我是路易斯・阿姆斯特朗  悉尼・巴特先生
Well, here is Louis Armstrong, Mister Sdyney Bechet.
听过我的美妙演奏
All the boys gonna step aside.
所有人都会臣服一旁
When they hear this song this alligator play.
听啊
Listen!
如我所愿  变成人类
When I'm human, as I hope to be.
牛儿回家前  我会一直吹
I'm gonna blow this horn till the cows come home.
人人都向我鞠躬致敬
And everyone's gonna bow down to me.
谢谢  谢谢  谢谢
Thank you! Thank you! Oh, thank you!
宝贝  我也爱你
I love you too, baby!
当我变回自己  我要随心所欲
When I'm myself again, I want just the life I had.
这个主意不错
That doesn't sound too bad.
红发女郎  黑肤美女
A red head on my left arm.
左拥右抱
A brunette on my right
一两个金发美女手持蜡烛
A blonde or two to hold the candles.
就应该这样
And that seems just about right.
路易斯
Eh, Louis?
人生苦短
Life is short.
岁月穿梭
When you're done, you're done.
人生在世  理应享受
We're on this Earth to have some fun.
事事如此
And that's the way things are.
跟我说说  兄弟
Tell me, brother!
当我变回人类  我肯定会变回去
When I'm human, and I'm gonna be.
还要像以前一样风流倜傥
I'm gonna tear it up like I did before.
这才是皇室的待遇
That's a royal guarantee.
你要结婚了
You are getting married.
好吧
Oh... right.
不能再招蜂引蝶了
I just have to leave a string of butterfly behind me.
你会变得谦虚
Your modesty becomes you.
充满责任感
And your sense of responsibility.
我通过努力得来一切
I worked hard for everything I got.
事情本该如此
And that's the way it supposed to be.
当我变回人类  至少我会那样
When I'm a human being, at least I'll act like one.
若每日尽力做到最好
If you do your best each and every day,
好事就会顺心如意
good things are sure to come your way.
一分耕耘  一分收获
What you give is what you get.
父亲的箴言  片刻不忘
My daddy sad that and now I'll never forget.
希望你也能改变
And I amend it to you.
当我们变成人类  肯定能成功
When we're humans and we're gonna be.
我要吹响号角
I'm gonna blow my horn.
我要过得更好
I'm gonna live a high life.
我要尽力追寻梦想
I'm gonna do my best to take my place in the Sun.
当我们变回人类
When we're human.
亲爱的纳温王子
Oh, Prince Naveen dear.
对于昨晚的青蛙事件
I'm positively modified you had to endured
我非常抱歉
that frog fiasco last night.
如果你是王位继承人
Well, when your next in line for the throne,
你要有豹一般迅猛的身手
you'll poised like panther.
必须要对意外情况有所准备
Ready to expect the unexpected.
你的耳朵
Your ear?
怎么了
Why?
这里蚊子太多了
There are plenty of mosquitoes.
到处都是
Everywhere.
请听我说
Please.
夏洛特小姐
Miss Charlotte,
我再也无法忽视内心的悸动
I can no longer ignore the throbbing of my heart.
我们相处时日虽短
Even our time together is been brief,
却令我感觉身处天堂
the experience's heavenly.
谢谢  纳温
Many thanks. Thanks, Naveen.
你的话让我害羞了
It got me blushing like it's...
我能否有幸娶你
Would you be the honoured of
做马耳其顿的王妃呢
becoming Princess of Maldonia?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
从未如此认真过
That's a pledge.
我愿意
Yes!
我当然愿意嫁给你
Oh, I would definitely marry you.
需要请好多人参加婚礼
Oh, there's so much to place in the guest list.
晚礼服  音乐  鲜花  鞋子
The dress, the music, the flowers, the shoes.
我们要筹备一场婚礼舞会
We're gonna have ourselves a party growing.
不
No!
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
拉瑞  因为你放跑了我们的青蛙王子
Because somebody let our froggy prince go, Larry.
还好我还可以
I'm reduced to asking for help
请另一边的朋友帮忙
from my friends on the other side.
你的餐馆会有
Now this restaurant of yours,
龙虾沙拉吗
is it gonna have a etouffee?
海鲜h饭  秋葵汤  都会有的
Jambalaya, gumbo, it's gonna have it all.
一直想吃红豆米饭
Always wanted to try red bean and rice.
火腿奶酪三明治  可怜的孩子
Muffuletta, poor boy.
别说了  路易斯
Stop, Louis.
你们两个说的我都饿了
You two are making me so very hungry.
有意思
Interesting.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
你把食物吓跑了
You are frightening the food.
看来就是这样
This is how it gonna looks.
什么
What?
不  不
Oh no...
No, no, no...
这决不可能
There is no way
在同一天吻了青蛙后  又想吃虫子
I'm kissing a frog and eating a bug on the same day.
不
Oh no...
你好
Hello...
等等
Hold still.
别扯了
Stop pulling.
你让我很难受
You are making me very difficult.
你们找到吃的了吗
You all found anything to eat yet?
天哪
Oh my...
别动
Hang on.
交给老路易斯来解决吧
Old Louis has got this covered.
不  不  不
No. No. No...
这样如何
How's that?
本来能更好点的
This could be a little better.
知道我们需要什么吗
You know what this needs?
尖木棍
A sharp stick.
我马上回来
Be right back.
这都是你的错
This is all your fault.
我的错  是我的错吗
My fault? My fault?
-我告诉你  -闭嘴听我说
- Let me tell you something... - Now listen!
我本可以过上好日子的
I would have a wonderful life...
看看你
Well, look at you.
姑娘  你和你的男友
Wow, girl. I bet you and your boyfriend
看上去很配
do look good, way a run
不  他不是我男朋友
No... he ain't my boyfriend.
我是马耳其顿王子
I'm Prince of Maldonia.
你们就别睁着眼睛说瞎话了
Never tried a little lie in this situation yo.
抱歉
Excuse me.
再试一次
One more time now.
这回好多了
That looks better yeah.
孩子们  别紧张  我不会爆炸的
Oh, it's okay, baby. I don't explode me.
我不是爆竹
I ain't not firecracker.
只不过我的屁股会在晚上发光
I just got my big butt glowing in the night.
女人喜欢大屁股的男人
Women like a man with a big back pouch.
你们的情形的确有点复杂
Oh, you've done this a real good for sure.
怎么让你们脱身呢
Now where did it go to end?
快了
Near.
等等  孩子
Hang on, chap.
我要进去一下
I'm gonna go in a little to this here...
进去一点  拽出来
Go in all and get them out.
你们自由啦
You're free to go.
请允许我自我介绍一下
Last time I introduce myself.
我叫雷蒙德
My name is Raymond.
但你们可以叫我雷
But you can call me Ray.
恕我直言  但你的口音  很搞笑
Pardon me, but your accent... it's funny, you know.
算你说对了
Okay, champ bro.
我在长沼土生土长
Born and breed in the bayou.
一看你们就是外地人
You all must be new around here.
事实上
Actually,
我们从很远很远的地方来
we are from a place far, far away from this world.
去休息吧
Go to bed!
一二三四
1, 2, 3, 4.
不不不
A... No, no, no...
我们是人类
We are people.
白马王子
Prince Charming here
中了巫术变成了青蛙
got himself turned into a frog by a voodoo witch doctor.
原来是这样
Well, there you go!
我们正要去找欧迪婆婆
And we were on our way to Mama Odie's.
希望她可以
We think maybe she can...
欧迪婆婆
Mama Odie?
你们走错方向了
You're heading the wrong direction here.
哪个蠢材告诉你们走这条路的
Now what kind of dumb head told you all to go this way?
我找到木棍了
I found the stick!
路易斯  雷告诉我们
Louis, Ray here says you've been taking us
你带错路了
in a wrong direction.
我  对地形  地理
I was... well, listen, I was confused by the topography,
地势不太熟悉
and the... geography and the... chorography...
长沼第一法则
First rule of the bayou,
绝不要让短嘴鳄带路
you never take directions from a gator.
让我和同伴们带路如何
What if me and my nation of the hip show you all the way?
太漂亮了
Ah, [speaks Maldonian]
所有人准备
10 thousand ready!
准备好为他们带路了吗
Are you ready for a little bayou data go?
你准备好就出发  雷表哥
Ready where you are, Cousin Ray!
好的  璐璐
Alright, Lulu!
我们出发吧  亲爱的
Let's get doing, darling!
来吧  伙计们
Come on, Chap.
跟着亮光的屁股走
Just follow the flashing butt!
我们来带路
We're gonna take ya down,
我们要带你们到达终点
We're gonna take ya all the way down!
我们来带路
We're gonna take ya down,
我们要带你们到达终点
We're gonna take ya all the way down!
走进长沼
Going down the bayou.
全程为你们带路
To lead you all the way.
我们有一个大家庭
We got the whole family.
比比表兄
Cousin Bibi.
普特洛表兄
Cousin Putro.
还有奶奶
Oh, grandmamma oh.
开始发光吧
Your light on!
大家一起
We are going to do it together.
我们这样带路
Now here that's how we do.
我和乐队  乐队和我
Me and the band and the band and me.
我们和你在一起
We'll all be there for you.
我们给你们领路
We're gonna take ya'.
我们全程给你们领路
We're gonna take you all the way down.
我们知道方向  我们与你们同行
We know where you're going and we're going with you.
全程为你们带路
Taking you all the way.
走进长沼
Going down the bayou.
全程为你们带路
Taking you all...you know.
快点
Come on, yo!
跟上队伍
Keep that line going.
保持队形
And the line's going.
没错  你的队形
Yeah, your line...
朋友  我知道已经让你们帮了很多忙
Friends, I know I'm in hug to you all pretty deep already.
不过看起来我们的小青蛙王子迷路了
But it seems our little froggy prince lost his way.
我需要你们帮我把它找回来
And I need your generous assistance to get him back.
我懂你们的意思
I hear you.
对你们有什么好处对吧
Now, what's in it for you 'all?
只要我搞定了拉布福老爹
Well, as soon as I dispose "Big Daddy" La Bouff,
我就能统治这个小镇
then I'm gonna run this town.
可以将整个新奥尔良城
I'll have the entire city of New Orleans
握在手中
in the palm of my hand.
你们就可以获得他们所有的灵魂
And you'll have all the wayward souls,
来满足你们内心那些阴暗的欲望
your dark little heart's desire.
你们一定会喜欢的  不是么
You all love that, don't you?
所以  就这么说定了吧
So, we got ourselves a deal?
现在听我说
Now we're talking!
我们要去把那只青蛙找回来
We're gonna find ourselves a frog.
搜遍每一个角落
Search everywhere!
不管长沼还是驻地
The bayou, the quarter.
把他活捉回来
Bring him to me alive.
他必须活着才行
I need his heart pumping.
现在出发吧
For now.
找到他
Find it!
仔细找
Third squiz.
我们要回去了
I'm taking them back to way.
很高兴认识你们
Nice meeting you.
再见了小家伙
Bye bye, Puggy.
再见  路易斯
Bye bye, Louis.
还有别忘了让伊万杰琳在那儿等我
And don't forget to tell Evangeline wait right there.
再见
Bonjour!
你女朋友吗
That's your girl?
我女朋友  不是不是
Oh, no... my girl?
她是伊万杰琳
That's Evangeline.
伊万杰琳?
Evangeline?
她是世界上最美的萤火虫
She's the most prettiest firefly ever did glow.
我每天晚上都和她聊天
You know I talk to Evangeline almost every night.
她喜欢聆听  不爱说话
She got sound, don't say much.
我很确定
And I know in my heart.
总有一天  我们会在一起的
Someday, we're gonna be together, yeah.
真甜蜜
Oh, that's so sweet.
没错  很甜蜜
Yes, so sweet.
别这么快就下结论  伙计
Just do not settle down so quickly, my friend.
沼泽地里的萤火虫还有很多呢
There are plenty of fireflies in the swamp.
怎么了
What?
我被灌木丛里的刺扎到了
Prick of bush has just got me!
我不行了
Get it down!
不行啦
黑暗正侵蚀着我
The darkness, it's closing in!
好冷啊
I'm so cold!
你能别动吗  大块头
Will you hold still, you big baby?
我只是碰了碰而已
I touched it yet.
快看那两只欢蹦乱跳的
Oh, take a look at them, the two jumpers.
我感觉已经尝到他们大腿的味道了
I can taste their frog legs already.
拿他们蘸着贝卡酱吃
Like them taste real good with the sauce bercha',
对吧  爸爸
right pa?
你小声点儿
You keep quiet!
和我想的完全一样
My thoughts exactly do things.
我们该去抓点青蛙了
It's time to catch us some frogs.
知道吗服务生
You know, waitress,
我终于知道你有什么问题了
I have finally figured out what is wrong with you.
是吗
Have you now?
你根本不知道如何寻欢作乐
You do not know how to have fun.
对吧  必须得有人告诉你这些
There. Somebody had to say it.
谢谢  正好我也找到你的问题所在
Thank you, 'cause I figured out what your problem is too.
我  过于优秀了  对吧
I am... too wonderful?
错  你是个没钱没品又懒惰的呆子
No, you're a no-count, plundering, lazy bump on a log.
真无趣
Kill joy.
你说什么
What'd you say?
没什么
Ah, nothing.
卑微的严肃小姐
Miss stick in the mud.
听着先生
Listen here, mister.
当你在你的象牙宫殿里
Miss stick in the mud has had to work
用着银勺子
two jobs her whole life
被无数侍女簇拥着的时候
while you've been sucking on a silver spoon
卑微的严肃小姐不得不靠加班养家
chasing chamber maids around your...your ivory tower!
事实上它是抛光的大理石
Actually, it's polished marble.
我抓到了一只  伙计们
Wow, I got me one, boys!
去把那只小的也抓走
Go get the little one over there!
他们有枪
They're with guns!
看啊  达尼尔
Look at him, big Darnell.
我会好好地为你准备晚餐的
I will make a gold ready with your dinner...
不不不
No, no, no...
小虫子就要做小虫子该做的事
A bug got to do what a bug got to do.
我最后的一颗牙也要掉了
I think I've done with my favourite tooth.
达尼尔  我来帮你了
Darnell I'm gonna help you.
老爸  我抓到了一只
Oh hoo. Pa, I got one!
你给我老实点
You quiet down!
你的那只怎么了
What happened to yours?
你给我闭嘴
Shut your crap, will you?
自由啦
Free!
老爸  你听到那个诡异的声音了吗
Pa, did you hear that suspicious sound?
是啊
Yeah.
我当然听到了
I sure did.
你们两个在看什么
What'd you two looking at?
就差一点
Just missed it.
我会打到他的
I will take him down.
我的天哪
Thank god
我来
I got this.
趁现在  快跑
Now go!
你在做什么
What did you...
别别别
No, no, no...
不要啊
Don't do it!
看这个
Watch this.
又没打到
Missed.
真没见过你们俩这样的青蛙
You two ain't like no frogs I ever seen.
他们还真聪明
They're smart.
我们还会说话呢
And we talk, too.
你没事吧  小虫子
You're alright there, little bug?
我没事
I'm fine.
你的口臭差点杀了我
But your breath nearly kill me to death.
你能不能帮忙
Would you mind?
我帮你搞定  兄弟
I got you covered, bro.
好多了啊  小东西
Much applies peewee.
屁股下面这些呢
Now, how about the lower side?
我们还会说话  我喜欢这句
And we talk too, I like it!
你其实还蛮幽默的嘛
You're secretly funny.
不是个卑微的严肃小姐了吗
Not a stick in the mud?
-那个  我的意思是  -快说  快说
- Well, I was going...  - Say it, say it.
好吧  其实你不是
Alright, you're not exactly...
我听不见
I can't hear you.
不好意思  你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
并非一个非常严肃的小姐
... a complete stick deep in the mud.
轻点  轻点
Easy, easy.
这个卡得很深  等等
This one in there. Hold on.
我的天
Holy...
我知道我们想快点到欧迪婆婆那里
I know we gotta get to Mama Odie like a little speed.
但是这个意外
but this particular extra occasion
还需要一点时间
gonna take a while, yeah.
可怜的路易斯
Oh, poor Louis.
你知道怎样能让我感觉好点么
You know what would make me feel better.
小龙虾沾着蛋黄酱
Crawfish smutted in Remoulade Sauce.
发发慈悲吧
Mercy!
还有几个
Gotta a little more
或者鳕鱼也可以
Some of the flosser sprinkle with prawn.
妈妈咪呀
Oh, Mama!
沼泽秋葵汤如何
How about some swamp Gumbo?
那也不错
That'll do.
听起来不错
Sound delicious.
我想喝点开胃酒
I'll start a pre-dinner cocktail
和一盘开胃菜
and something to nibble on.
不过我还是等等吧  谢谢
But I'll wait. Thanks.
不不不
No, no, no...
至高无上的殿下
Your royal highness,
你要负责切这些蘑菇
you are going to mince these mushrooms.
做  做什么
Do... do what?
切蘑菇
Mince the mushrooms!
快动手
Hop to it!
这太可笑了
This is ridiculous.
-你开始切了吗  -好吧
- Are you mincing?  - Alright!
放轻松
Relax.
还好嘛
What.
让我来  殿下
Step aside, mister.
学着点
Watch and learn.
好吧
Oh, alright.
就是这样
There you go.
那个  我  我从来没做过这些
You know, I've never done anything like this before.
真的假的
Really?
住在城堡里  所有事都是准备好的
When you live in a castle, everything is done for you.
一直都是  他们帮你穿衣服  喂你吃饭
All the time, they... dress you, they feed you,
帮你开车  还帮你刷牙
drive you, brush your teeth.
可怜的孩子
Oh, poor baby.
我承认在这之前我感觉挺好的
I admit it was a charm life and
直到父母剥夺了我的继承权
until the day my cut me off
我突然发现  我什么都不会做
Suddenly I realised... I don't know how to do anything.
你的蘑菇还是切的不错的  殿下
You got to make yourself a very decent mushroom, mincer.
你这么觉得吗
Oh, you think so?
要不断练习
Keep practising.
然后我就会喜欢上你了
And you'll be just my type.
-真的吗  -才怪
- Really?  - No.
拜托  这算什么  你伤了一只青蛙的心
Oh, come on. What was that? That was below the frog frail.
他们说  你好
They said Hello?
你说  什么
And you said what?
然后你说  把你的丑鱼带进来
And you said get your ugly fish in.
还有人要汤吗
Anyone for seconds?
这个真的很好喝
That was magnificent.
你真的很有天赋
You truly have a gift.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
她来了
There she is.
世界上最美的萤火虫
The sweetest firefly in all creation.
伊万杰琳
Evangeline?
我也想见见她
I wanna meet this girl!
她在哪儿呢
Where's she at?
你一定不能错过她
Oh, you can't miss her.
她就在你面前闪耀呢
She glows right up there in front of you.
看着她在天空中闪烁
Look out she lights on the sky.
我亲爱的伊万杰琳
My babe Evangeline.
在我看来
Oh, that I know...
虽离我遥远  但只属于我
So far above me yet I know her heart belongs to only me.
我喜欢你
J'adore.
I adore you.
我爱你
Je t'aime.
I love you.
伊万杰琳
Evangeline.
我只是在翻译
Just translating!
你是我的夜之女王
You're my queen of the night.
如此寂静  如此明亮
So still, so bright.
还有什么和她一样美丽呢
That someone is beautiful as she.
美好的爱情  像我这样
Good love, someone like me.
不  我不会跳舞
Oh, no. I don't dance.
爱让梦想成真  没错
Love always finds a way, it's true.
我从没跳过舞
I've never danced.
我爱你  伊万杰琳
And I love you, Evangeline.
既然我可以切东西  你就可以跳舞
If I can mince, you can dance.
爱很美丽
Love is beautiful.
爱很奇妙
Love is wonderful.
爱就是一切  是吧
Love is everything, do you agree?
看着她在天空中闪耀
Look out she lights on the sky.
我爱你  伊万杰琳
I love you, Evangeline.
我们只是跳了支舞而已
Lots have getting us up for one hack of a dance partner.
我们最好还是冷静冷静
We... uhm...we best be portion on.
蒂亚纳
Tiana!
纳温
Naveen!
不不不
No, no, no!
我这个197岁的盲老太太身手不错吧
Not bad for a 197-year-old blind lady.
你们知道是谁
Now, which one of you know the
惹到影子巫师了吗
theory of been messing with the Shadow Man?
真高兴能找到你  欧迪婆婆
We're so glad we found you, Mama Odie.
路易斯和我们说了很多你的事
Man, Louis here had been telling us all about you.
我们走了很久才找到你
We have been travelling quite a long way
你一定不知道我们都经历了些什么
and you can't imagine what we've been through.
还有我们  我们  我们听说你
And we... and, and, and... we heard that you...
小家伙
Juju!
过来吧  你这个坏孩子
Come on over here, you bad boy.
来点甜蜜的
Be a little sugar now.
你很爱你妈妈  对吧
You just love your mama, don't you?
很高兴再次见到你  雷
Good to see you again, Ray.
你祖母怎样了
How's your grandma?
哦  她很好
Oh, she's fine.
在邻居问题上还有点小问题
Got into a trouble for flying into the neighbour again.
我喜欢那女人
Oh, I like that gal.
欧迪婆婆
Mama Odie.
我们也不想浪费您太多的时间
We don't wanna take up too much of your time.
要点糖果吗
You all want some candy?
还是算了
Oh, not pretty.
不用了  谢谢
No thank you.
真是太遗憾了嘛
Then that is too bad!
这可是很特别的糖果哦
This is special candy.
它可以让你们变回人类
Which will turn you back into human.
-等下 -等等  别  别吃掉
- No... Please!  - Wait, no... please, don't take it!
我只是在和你们开玩笑而已
I'm just messing with you all.
你怎么知道我们想变回
How on earth did you know that we wanted to turn back...
欧迪婆婆
Mama Odie?
小家伙
Juju!
你怎么不告诉我我的汤好了
Why didn't you tell me that my Gumbo is burning?
你确定这就是那个住在长沼树洞里的
You're sure that this is the right bright voodoo lady
那个聪明婆婆
who lives in the bottom tree of the bayou?
非常肯定
Pretty sure.
真不敢相信
Can't believe this.
看来又得重做了
Got to do it back around here.
欧迪妈妈  如果你
Mama Odie, if you...
尝一下
Taste this!
怎么样
Well?
再加一勺迪巴斯卡酱
Heat it hotter with a cup of shot of
和蜂蜜然后加热
Debasaki and the bee's sneeze.
我们能不能
Now, can we...
小家伙
Juju!
美味极了
Yeah! That's got some zaim to it!
这就是我想要的
That's just what it needed.
你们现在明白自己想要什么了吗
Now, you all figure out what you need?
就像你说的那样  欧迪婆婆
It's just like what you said, Mama Odie.
我们想变回人类
We need to be human.
啊  你们只需说出你们要的东西
Ah! You only got to say you all need.
你们只想着怎么变回人类
You want to be human.
但你们却不知道你们需要的是什么
But you're blind to what you need.
我们想要什么  我们需要什么
What we want, what we needed.
都一样嘛  对吧
It's all the same thing, yes.
一样吗  才怪
It's the same thing? No!
听我说
You listen to your mama now.
你们的长相并不重要
Don't matter what you look like.
穿着也不重要
Don't matter what you wear.
手上戴几个戒指
How many ring you got on your finger.
我们不在乎 没错
We don't care. No,
我们不在乎
we don't care!
你们从哪来并不重要
Don't matter where you come from.
你们是什么也不重要
Don't even matter what you are.
是狗  是猪  是奶牛  是羊
A dog, a pig, a cow, a goat.
我们什么都不缺
Had 'em all in here (we had 'em all in here)
他们都知道他们要什么
And they all knew what they wanted.
想让我做什么
What they wanted me to do.
我告诉他们究竟需要什么
I told them what they needed.
就像我会告诉你们一样
Just like I be telling you.
你们得再好好想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
探究自我
Find out who you are.
你们得再好好想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
其实并不难
It really ain't that far
了解了自己就能
When you find out who you are,
了解自己的需求
you'll find out what you need.
蓝天和阳光能证明这些
Blue skies and sunshine guaranteed.
你们得再好好想想
You got to dig (dig).
青蛙王子是个富裕的孩子
Prince froggy is a rich little boy.
你想再次变得富裕
You wanna be rich again.
但这样不会让你变得开心
That ain't gonna make you happy now,
以后会让你开心吗
did it make you happy then?
不会
No!
金钱会让你迷失自我
Money ain't got no soul.
金钱让你迷失心灵
Money ain't got no heart.
你要学会自我控制
All you need is some self-control.
给自己一个全新的开始
Make yourself a brand new start.
你们得再好好想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
马上就要想到了
Don't have far to go.
你们得再好好想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
告诉大家婆婆这样告诉你
Tell the people, mama told you so.
不知道你会如何理解
Can't tell you what you'll find
也许爱情能让你发现自我
Maybe love will grant you piece of mind.
再想想你就会发现
Dig a little deeper and you'll know
青蛙小姐
Miss froggy?
是的
Ma'am?
我可以说两句吗
May I have a word?
当然  女士
Yes, ma'am.
据我了解  你的状况有点难办
You're a hard one, that's what I heard.
你父亲是个可爱的人
Your daddy was a loving man.
一直以家庭为重
Family through and through
你是他的女儿
You your daddy's daughter.
他有的一切你都有
What he had in him you got in you.
你们还得再想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
对你来说有点儿难
For you it's gonna be tough.
你们还得再想想
You got to dig a little deeper.
想的还是不够深
You ain't dug near far enough.
深入地想想自己
Dig down deep inside yourself.
你会发现你自己的需求
You'll find out what you need.
蓝天和阳光能证明这些
Blue skies and sunshine guaranteed.
把窗子打开
Open up the windows.
让光线照进来吧孩子们
Let in the light children.
蓝天和阳光
Blue skies and sunshine.
能证明这些
Guaranteed.
好了青蛙小姐
Well, miss froggy,
现在知道你需要什么了吗
do you understand what you need now, child?
我知道了  欧迪婆婆
Yes, I do, Mama Odie!
我还要投入更多的努力
I need to dig a little deeper
然后努力工作想办法开自己的餐厅
and work even harder to get my restaurant.
不是吧
No.
没关系  再来一次
Alright, yo. One more time!
你们长什么样并不重要
It don't matter what you look like.
穿什么也
It don't...
没人愿意和雷一起唱  好吧
Nobody gonna sing with Ray... okay.
如果你们还想变回人类
Well, if you still long to be human,
只有一个方法
there's only one way.
秋葵汤秋葵  快快显灵
Gumbo, Gumbo, lead the path.
我们需要你的意见
We need a precious.
你发现什么了
What you got?
洛特吗
Lotte?
不过她也不是个公主啊
But she's not a princess.
闭嘴  看着秋葵汤
Oh, shut up and look at the Gumbo.
对了
That's right.
她父亲拿着皇冠进来了
Big Daddy's came with the mind cooperate.
所以洛特就是个公主了
So that makes Lotte a princess.
这样也算
Does that count?
当然算
Yeah, it does.
但只能持续到午夜而已
But only till midnight.
到了黎明就失效了
Win more than an aurora.
我的天哪
[speaks Maldonia]
快点行动吧
Hop along.
你必须在午夜前找到她并让她吻你
You only got till then to get the Princess to kiss you.
一旦她吻了你  啪
Once she does... boom!
你们就会变回人类了
You'll boom to a human.
午夜
Midnight?
那我们快没时间了
Oh, that doesn't give us much time at all!
那我呢  婆婆
What about me, mama?
我也想变成人类
I wanna be human too.
这样我就能和大师们一起玩爵士了
So I can play jazz with the big boys!
我想要手指脚趾还有肚子
I want fingers, and toes, and a belly button...
不是这种凸出来的  而是那种凹进去的
not the kinds that sticks out; but that kinds that goes in.
你也得再好好想想
You dig a little deeper.
以后就你就会发现你的需求了
You'll find every time you need.
好了好了好了
Come on, come on, come on!
别像女人那么婆婆妈妈的
You like a woman in here.
祝你好运  快点游回去吧
All the best. Get to swimming.
等一下
Wait!
我有个更好的注意
I got a better idea.
他们有枪
They got guns!
早上好伙计
One great morning boy.
天  你的装扮实在是太棒了
Dang! That is one killer griller costume.
大鳄鱼  你会吹这小号吗
Hey gator, can you blow that horn?
来吧  跟我们走
Come on, sit here with us.
我们可以吹口琴
We play harmonica.
我们绝不能错过这个
We can't miss this.
小路易斯终于要和大师们一起演奏啦
Little Louis can finally play with the big boys.
纳温  你要来吗
Naveen, you coming?
我  我马上就来
I'll... I'll catch up with you later.
伊万杰琳  我是否可以看着蒂亚纳的眼睛
Evangeline, can I just look Tiana in the eyes
然后说
and say
我愿意牺牲一切
I wanna do whatever it takes
来完成你的梦想
to make all your dreams come true
因为  因为我爱你
because... because I love you.
天哪  你居然敢向我的女人表白
Wow... You make a goo-goo out of my girl?!
-不不  等下 -你怎么敢
- No, no... wait! - What makes you
没有  等等
No,no... wait!
我没有爱上伊万杰琳
I'm not in love with Evangeline!
我爱的是蒂亚纳
I'm in love with Tiana!
我就知道
I knew it! I knew it! I knew it!
过来过来
You come here, you.
我不会娶夏洛特・拉布福小姐的
I can no longer marry Miss Charlotte LaBouff.
我会想其他办法帮蒂亚纳开饭店的
I will find another way to get Tiana a restaurant.
你们会生出一只蝌蚪来
You can have a tadpole.
-找份工作  -看看你
- Get a job. - Look at you.
两份也行  不然三份
Maybe two, maybe three.
我等不及要告诉蒂亚纳了
I can't wait to tell Tiana!
不不不  我想亲自告诉她  一个人
No, no... I must tell her, alone.
好吧
Right.
说得没错
You are right.
你要带我去哪儿
Where are you taking me?
我想  为了庆祝我们最后一个青蛙之夜
Oh, I just... wanted to show you a little something
想给你看点儿东西
to celebrate our last night together as frogs.
这么多年来
All my years,
从没有人对我这么好过
no one's ever done anything like this for me.
有  有点儿大  是吧
It... It is too much, isn't it?
谢谢你  蝴蝶先生
Thank you, Bow.
我本以为这样会很好看呢
I thought it was a nice touch.
就当你没看见吧
Pretend you did not see that.
好了  请坐
Please, please. Sit down.
这是什么
What's this?
看
Ta-da!
你切的
You minced!
没错
I did!
你对我的影响很大
You've had quite an influence on me.
我和很多女人交往过
Which is amazing because I have dated
但是你最最特别
thousands of women and...
没有很多  只有两个  三个  其他女人
No, like two, three... just other women.
算了  听我说
And anyway, listen.
没人比你更特别了
You could not be more different.
其实你  你是个爷们
You know, you are practically... one of the guys!
不不不  你当然不是男人
No no no! You are not a guy!
我还是从头说过吧
Let me begin again!
我今晚不在状态
I am not myself tonight.
蒂亚纳
Tiana!
不好意思  声音太大了
Sorry, that was loud.
真是太糟糕了
This is a disaster.
没有  你真可爱
No, it's cute.
蒂亚纳  我
Tiana, I...
快看啊
There it is.
你的餐厅
Your restaurant?
那是多么令人兴奋的一件事啊
Oh, can you just picture all live like the fourth of July.
没错  爵士乐
Yes! Jazz!
整个餐厅都会响起音乐
Pouring out to every window.
应该更优雅点儿
It should be elegant.
可以优雅一些  但要恰到好处
You gotta keep it loose, thought gotta let it swing.
你很在行嘛  你可以来帮我演奏
You know good, you gotta let it playing.
真的吗
Really?
你想让我去演奏吗
You'll let me perform?
我去问问店长
I'll talk to the owner.
店长同意了
Owner says yes.
她当然会
She does that!
全世界的人都会赶来
Also gotta become a gather from all walks' life
只为了尝尝我们的美食
just to get a taste of our food.
我们的美食
Our food?
哦  我不是这个意思  是我父亲
Huh? Oh, no, no. My daddy.
他一直想开一家自己的餐厅
He always wanted to open his restaurant.
可惜他去世得早  无法亲眼看到
He died before he could see it happen.
有了你的帮忙  明天我的梦想就能实现了
Tomorrow, with your help, my dream is finally coming true.
明天
Tomorrow?
如果我明天一早不能筹到钱的话
If I don't deliver that money first thing tomorrow,
我的餐厅就没了
I'll lose this place forever.
蒂亚纳我爱
Tiana, I love...
我喜欢你说起你梦想时的样子
the way you like that when you talk about your dream.
如此美好的梦想
A dream that it is so beautiful.
我  我保证我会不惜一切
I... I promise I will do whatever it takes
帮你实现愿望的
to make it come true.
我  我去找他们几个
I'll... I'll go roundup the boys.
伊万杰琳  我一直都很清楚我想要什么
Evangeline, I've always been so sure about what I want
直到现在
and now I...
我该怎么办呢
What do I do?
请告诉我吧
Please tell me.
亲爱的纳温王子
Prince Naveen, darling?
你得快点啦
You'd better hurry up.
我们明早的婚礼可不能迟到呀
Don't wanna be late for our morning gown wedding.
我正在穿礼服
I'm getting dressed.
等一会儿  亲爱的  我马上就好
Just a few moments, it's fine dearest Char.
好吧甜心  我们在油轮上等你
Okay honey Veen, we will be waiting in the packet.
老爸  停车
Daddy, stop the car!
天哪  我被诅咒了
Oh my heavens! I'm doomed!
不  拉瑞  我才是被诅咒那个
No, Larry! I'm the one who's doomed!
除非我们把那只青蛙的血
Unless we get that frog's blood in...
我们终于重回正轨啦
We are back in business, boys!
拿开你的手
Just keep the hands from me!
劳  劳伦斯吗
Law... Lawrence?
对啊  抓好他
Oh yeah. Hold still, your heaven.
雷
Ray!
看见纳温了吗
Have you seen Naveen?
看看你
Look at you.
戒指呢
Where's the ring at?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
老大不说  我也不会
Well, the captain say none,
因为老雷的嘴巴像鼓一样
I am gonna say none cause old Ray is
被封得严严的
seal up high in the drum
我什么都不会说的
and none out of me, no.
雷
Ray.
好吧  老大说他不想娶夏洛特而想娶你
Okay, captain say he ain't gonna marry Charlotte but you.
当你们俩得到那个吻变成人之后
When they two got kiss and you both turn into human.
他会去找工作  你也有了餐厅
He's gonna find a job, you get that restaurant.
我好像说得太多了  是吧
I said too much, didn't I?
刚刚好  雷
You said just enough, Ray!
伊万杰琳  谢谢你
Thank you, Evangeline.
他刚刚想要向我求婚
He was trying to propose!
所以才弄得一团糟
That's what all those fuss was about.
而我一直认为他想和富裕的千金结婚
And here I thought all he wanted was to marry a rich girl.
我们这是在找什么
What are we looking for, ya?
你只需要留神点
You just keep your eyes out!
寻找比我们大好几倍的
For the biggest, gloriest globe with
光彩亮丽的公主
the multigraph princess
她会去亲一只青蛙
about to kiss herself a... a frog.
亲爱的朋友
Dearly beloved,
我们聚到这里参加这次盛会
we all gathered here tonight in this fine celebration
见证王子和这位女士
to join together this prince and this young woman
的完美结合
in holy naturally.
不  这不可能是真的
Oh no, this can't be real, darling.
为什么你还是青蛙呢
And how you can still be a frog?
欧迪婆婆说
Mama Odie, she said...
我知道你看到了什么  但是
I know what we seen with our eyes, but...
但我们得回去
We just go back there,
去让你的童话变成真的
we're gonna find out your fairytale come true.
不是你想什么  就能得到什么
Just because you wish for something, doesn't make it true.
就像我的伊万杰琳经常对我说的一样
It's like my Evangeline always says to me...
雷  伊万杰琳只是一颗星星
Evangeline is nothing but a star, Ray.
一个巨大的热气团  离这里十万八千里
A big ball of hot air, a million miles from here!
在受伤之前  面对现实吧
Open your eyes now, before you get hurt.
她只是在说气话而已
She's just speaking under a broken heart.
肯定是这样
That's all it is
快伊万杰琳
Come on, Evangeline.
我们来帮她看清真相
We go show her the truth.
如果你们中有谁不同意
If any of you objects to the union of the two.
要么现在说  要么永远都不说
Speak now or forever hold your keep.
我  我  我  我反对
Me! Me! Me! I object!
纳温王子  你愿意小夏为你的妻子吗
Do you, Prince Naveen takes Char to be your wife?
哥们儿  你要做的都做完了
Chap! What you do is done.
直到你们走到生命的尽头
... as long as you both shall live.
什么  我愿意  当然愿意
What? I do. Yes. I'm for it.
是你吗  老大
Is that you Cap?
雷  把我弄出来
Ray! Get me out of this box!
说话小声点
I can hear you.
我马上把你弄出来
I'm gonna get you out of this box.
直到生命的尽头
... as long as you both shall live.
我愿意
Oh, I do.
如果这样  在上帝的指引下
And so, by the power given to me.
我现在宣布
I now pronounce you...
拉瑞
Larry!
上帝啊  你没事儿吧
Oh goodness gracious! Are... you alright?
给我一点时间整理一下
I just need a moment to compose my tone.
真是个疯子
Shitty crackers!
劳伦斯  你为什么要这样做
Lawrence! Why are you doing this?
这是对你多年羞辱我的报复
It's payback for all those years of humiliation.
回到你的婚礼现场
Get your royal run back on that wedding cake
赶快完成它
and finish this deal!
他在做什么
Oh, what's he doing?!
阻止他
Stop him!
我不行
I can't!
我抓住了
I got it!
它也抓住我了
It got me too!
那个护身符
That talisman.
别挡道
Clear aside!
快  快
Come on come on!
雷
Ray?
喂  你怎么停下来了
Hey, why'd you stop?
这是一只真的鳄鱼
It's a real alligator!
雷
Ray?
这个证明我们看见的并不是事实
This proof what we saw ain't what we thought we saw!
这是什么
What is this?
这是一种巫术
It's a voodoo...
影子巫师创造了它然后把它
The Shadow Man, he produced it with the...
无论如何不能让影子巫师再拿到它
You can't let shadow man get this no matter what!
快跑  快跑
Now, run girl. Run!
别逼我点亮我的屁股
Don't make me light my butt!
我速度很快
I got it a lot of movement!
过来啊
Come here you!
下一个是谁
Who's next?
雷
Ray!
Ray?
让开
Back off!
不然我把这个摔成碎片
Or I'm gonna break this thing into a million pieces!
纳温
Naveen?
这比在长沼的沼泽地里
Now ain't this a whole lot better than hopping around
跳来跳去美好多了吧
the bayou for the rest of your life?
影子巫师
Shadow Man.
蒂亚纳  你真让我头痛
Got a headache to you, Tiana.
你为什么不要一个大一点的梦想呢
When you dream, you dream big.
看看这里
Just look at this place.
金碧辉煌
Would be the crown, jewel of the crystal scene.
你只要把我的小小法宝交出来
And all you got to do to make this a reality
这里就全都是你的了
is hand over that little talisman of mine.
不
No.
这  这可不行
This... This is not right.
别这样  亲爱的
Come on now, darling.
想想你所付出的一切
Think of everything you've sacrificed.
你要的一切就是
Girl, all you wanna do is...
我说过她不会去的
I told you she wouldn't come.
想想那些怀疑你能力的人说过的话
Think of all those they say who doubt you.
你不可能拥有这样一家餐厅
You ain't gotta get enough for the restaurant.
像你这样背景的女孩  还是放弃吧
Woman of your background, you better off will yet.
别忘了你可怜的老爸
And don't forget your poor daddy.
工作多么努力的男人啊
That was one hardworking man.
有时还要打两三份工
Double, sometimes triple shifts.
更别说他的劳累疲倦
Never let known how bored, tired and beat down
以及失败感
he really was.
爸爸
Daddy!
小宝贝
Hey! Baby case.
真遗憾  所有的辛勤劳累
Shame all that hard work
换来的只是坏掉了的苹果
didn't about much more than a busted apple,
一个秋葵汤锅
a gumbo pot
和一个从未实现的梦想
and a dream that never get off to back porch.
但是你
But you...
你现在可以让你可怜老爸的梦想成真
you can give your poor daddy everything he ever wanted.
来吧  蒂亚纳
Come on, Tiana.
你的梦想快实现了
You're almost there.
我爸爸从来没得到过他想要的
My daddy never did get what he wanted.
但需要的一切他都有了
But he had what he needed.
他有爱
He had love.
他知道什么是最重要的
Never lost sight of what was important.
别激动  小心
Easy with that, be careful!
我不会被你骗倒的
And neither will I!
你应该答应我的条件的
You should have taken my deal.
你的后半辈子只能当一只
Now you will spend the rest of your life
粘粘的小青蛙了
being a slime little frog.
我告诉你  影子巫师
I got news for you, Shadow Man.
这不是粘液
It's not slime.
这是保护粘胶
It's mucus!
不  不
No! No!
我怎么才能把债还清啊
How am I ever gonna pay back my debt?
朋友们
Friends!
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
不  还没呢
No! I'm not ready at all!
别这样
Get back to you.
我还有很多灵魂呢
I got lots of soul left.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
这只是计划里的一个小小失误
This is just a minor setback to major operation.
只要再找一个头骨
As soon as I find another skull,
我们就可以继续了
we will be back in business!
青蛙王子还被我锁着呢
I still got that frog prince lock away.
我只需要一点点时间
I just need a little more time.
不  求你们了  别这样
Oh, no... No please don't.
我只需要一点点时间
Just a little more time.
我保证会报答你们的
I promise you I'll pay you back.
我保证
I promise.
王子  纳温王子
Prince! Prince Naveen!
你的羞涩已经把我彻底惹怒了
Your shy and retiring bankruptcy is getting me angry!
你好  亲爱的
Hello, darling.
这里  下面
Please, down here!
让我  介绍一下我自己
Allow me... to introduce myself.
我才是真正的纳温王子殿下
I am the real Prince Naveen.
从马耳其顿来
... of Maldonia.
刚刚你说"王子"吗
Did you say 'prince'?
守卫  把这个怪物关到巴黎监狱去
Guards, drag this maggot down to the Paris Prison!
我是完全清白的
I am completely innocent.
影子巫师在我身上施了巫术
There is a shadow man put voodoo in me.
上帝啊
Goodness gracious!
太复杂了  是不是这样的
This is so much to absorb. Let me see if I got this right.
如果我在午夜前吻你
If I kiss you before midnight,
你和蒂亚纳就会重新变成人
you and Tiana will turn human again,
然后我们两个完成婚礼
and then we gonna get ourselves married
从此幸福快乐地生活在一起
and live happily ever after!
完结了
The end!
是的  差不多
Yeah, more or less.
但是记住
But remember,
你得给蒂亚纳
you must give Tiana all the money
足够的钱去开她自己的餐厅
she requires for her restaurant.
因为蒂亚纳
Because Tiana...
是我的伊万杰琳
She is my Evangeline.
随便你  甜心
Anything you want, sugar.
撅起嘴巴吧  小动物
Pucker up, buttercup!
等等
Wait!
蒂亚纳
Tiana?
别这样做
Don't do this.
我不得不这样  我们没时间了
I have to do this and we are running out of time!
我不会让你这样的
I won't let you!
这是让你梦想成真的唯一办法
It's the only way to get you your dream!
我的梦想
My dream?
没有你的话我的梦想是不完整的
My dream wouldn't be complete without you in it.
我爱你  纳温
I love you, Naveen.
不怕羞吗
Warts and all?
不怕羞
Warts and all.
我的一生读过好多关于真爱和童话的故事
All my life, I read about true love and fairytales.
小蒂  你找到了
Tia, you found it!
我会吻他的
I'll kiss him!
亲爱的  为了你  不用和我结婚
For you, honey! No marriage required.
天哪  或许时钟有一点快了
Oh my lord! M...maybe that old clock's a little fast!
真对不起
Oh, I'm so sorry!
蒂亚纳  纳温
Tiana! Naveen!
路易斯  这是什么
Louis, what is it?
影子巫师用脚踩在了雷身上
Shadow Man laid his paw on Ray
它伤得很厉害
He's hurt awful bad.
你们
Hey, you...
你们怎么还
How come you all are still...
雷  我们还是青蛙
We're staying frogs, Ray.
我们决定在一起了
And we are staying together.
亲爱的  真高兴你们可以这样
Oh, baby. I like that very much.
伊万杰琳也会高兴的
Evangeline like that too.
在众神的引领下
So about the power of destined in me.
我现在宣布这两只青蛙成为夫妻
I now pronounce you're frog and wife.
你们两个一起终老  你可以吻新娘了
You two hop along. Give your lovely wife your sugar.
恭喜
Congratulations.
真是太好了
This gonna be good.
就像我告诉你们的一样
Like I told you all.
吻一位公主将打破魔法
Kissing a princess will break the spell.
变成我妻子
The one who should become my wife.
会让你成为
That makes you...
一名公主
A princess.
你刚刚吻了一位属于你的公主
You just kissed yourself a princess.
我还要再做一次
And I'm about to do it again.
芬内兄弟地产
南方大地  有城一座
In the South Land, there's a city.
矗立河边
Way down on the river.
窈窕淑女  君子好逑
Where the women are very pretty and all the men deliver.
音乐悠扬
They got music.
此起彼伏
It's always playing.
从早到晚  整夜欢歌
Start in the day time, go all through the night.
若闻乐声
When you hear that music playing,
如闻我言  请君自便
hear what I'm saying and make it feel alright.
早就听说所有的王子都有弟弟
Heard of all the prince would have had a younger brother.
你说你多少岁来着
How old did you say you were?
六岁半
I'm six and a half.
那我还得等很久
Well, I'd waited this long.
邀友同行  并肩前往
Grab somebody, come on down.
手握画笔  美化城邦
Bring your paintbrush, we're painting the town.
香飘四溢
Oh, there's some sweetness going around.
梦想成真  在新奥尔良
Dreams do come true in New Orleans.